ARAVINDH MURUGESAN

Automation / Platform Engineering

Chennai, India. I aravindhstanley@gmail.com | https://aravindhstanley.github.io/

I'm an experienced automation and platform engineer with extensive understanding of infra structure, to ease the complexity and delivery times. Self driven and highly motivated team player to achieve the business goal.

Work Experience

2022 - Present

Assistant Manager, Platform Engineering | Tata Communications | Chennai, India.

- Responsible for designing highly available and up-to-date infrastructure for applications at scale.
- Develop and maintain **Infrastructure-as-Code** to expedite project delivery.
- Setup a production grade **Openstack** platform from the ground up with **Kolla Ansible**, while maintaining a downstream git to add our custom changes to Kolla.
- Create workflows and documentation for Openstack to assist our internal operations.
- Constantly involved in Openstack community to improve openstack toolings, especially with Kolla Ansible.
- Build internal cli tools for maintenance and **workflow automations**, mostly with python as the programming language of choice.
- Constantly perform Proof-of-Concept features to enhance customer experience and platform richness.
- Implement DevOps for platform with vast array of tools like **Ansible**, **Terraform**, **Git**, **Docker**, **Python and Golang**.
- Work with Elastic stack, log shippers like vector, for central observability and analysis.
- Explore and enable metrics reporting for overview and for data driven business decisions

2020 - 2023

Senior Engineer, Automation / DevOps / Python I Tata Communications I Chennai, India

- Develop a full stack application to manage, observe and interface with internal object cloud storage platform.
- Managing and implementing SwiftStack object storage (based on openstack swift) that scales massively, with the help of automations and deployments using Ansible / Python.
- Orchestrate data migration in the scale of several petabytes for platform migrations with automation programs to improve efficiency.
- Architect application design, with high proficiency in Python 3 and Go.
- Script platform maintenance (patches and upgrades) with Ansible and Python to reduce mundane activities to improve stability and engineering productivity.
- Maintaining automation code repository powered by Gitea.
- Dockerize conventional application for efficient utilisation of physical resources.

- Work and troubleshoot S3 compatible systems to manage data and backups.
- Deploy and work with Linux environments and configuration management
- Experience working with AWS services EC2, ELB, Route53.

2017 - 2020

Engineer, Cloud Storage / Automation I Tata Communications I Chennai, India

- Automation of L1 tickets Workflow and fix with ticket management to reduce support workloads
- IT Operations Linux (Ubuntu, RHEL derivates), Object Storage (Swift and S3)
- IT Operations Backup solution (Commvault)
- Create and maintain post deployment configurations with Ansible
- Automation scripting for OS for maintenance, patches, and firmware upgrades for baremetal Huawei servers.

Education

2013 - 2017

Bachelors in Electronics and Communications Engineering I SRM University I Chennai.

- Graduated in first class with a GPA of 8.6

Language

- Tamil (Native)
- English (Professional Fluency)